

Ph.D in Computer Vision and Deep Learning

□+39 334 8756245 | ■roberto.bigazzi.1995@gmail.com | #robertobigazzi.it | □ bigazzon | □ roberto-bigazzi

# Summary.

I'm a Post-Doc Researcher at the University of Modena and Reggio Emilia, in the AlmageLab research laboratory supervised by Professor Rita Cucchiara. The main topics of my research are Computer Vision and Deep Learning, particularly on Embodied AI tasks and challenges.

I pursued my Ph.D. at AlmageLab research laboratory after completing my Master's Degree in Computer Science and Engineering at the Polytechnic University of Milan, with Professor Marco Gribaudo. During my Ph.D. program, I spent a period as a visiting student researcher at Stanford University in the Autonomous Systems Lab (ASL) directed by Professor Marco Pavone.

# Knowledge and Technical Skills \_\_\_\_\_

**Domains** Visual Navigation, Multimodal Learning, Natural Language Processing, Reinforcement Learning, Deep Learning

**Programming** Python, Java, Javascript, C++, C#, C, MATLAB, SQL, Microcontroller Programming (Arduino)

Frameworks and Other PyTorch, OpenCV, Numpy, Pandas, ET;X, Scikit-learn, Tensorflow, Keras, ROS, Git, Android Programming, MySQL

**Languages** Italian (Mothertongue), English (Proficient *TOEIC (C1), FCE (B2)*)

# **Education**

#### University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Modena, Italy

POST-DOC RESEARCHER: COMPUTER VISION AND DEEP LEARNING

Mar. 2023 - present

· Research on Visual Navigation and Multimodal Learning (Embodied AI)

## **University of Modena and Reggio Emilia**

Modena, Ital

DOCTOR OF PHILOSOPHY IN INFORMATION AND COMMUNICATION TECHNOLOGIES: COMPUTER VISION AND DEEP LEARNING

Nov. 2019 - Mar. 2023

• Multimedia Data Learning at Almagelab under the supervision of Prof. Rita Cucchiara

Stanford University Stanford, California, United Sta

VISITING STUDENT RESEARCHER May 2022 - Aug. 2022

• Research on Visual Navigation at Autonomous Systems Lab (ASL) under the supervision of Prof. Marco Pavone

#### Polytechnic University of Milan Milan, Ital

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Sep. 2017 - Oct. 2019

• Thesis with Prof. Marco Gribaudo: "Enhancing Spatial Navigation in Robot-Assisted Surgery: a case study"

Technische Universität Wien Vienna, Austria

Erasmus+ Exchange Semester Oct. 2018 - Feb. 2019

Polytechnic University of Milan Milan, Italy

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering Sep. 2014 - Sep. 2017

# **Experience**

### AlmageLab - University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Modena, Italy

RESEARCH FELLOW Nov. 2019 - present

Research on Embodied Al during Doctorate at AlmageLab.

Prometeia Bologna, Italy

LECTURER Nov. 2021

Python and Machine Learning course for Banco BPM

IFOA Modena / Bologna Modena / Bologna, Italy

**LECTURER** Jan. 2021 - Apr. 2021

"Deep Learning, Artificial Intelligence e Neurolinguistic Processing" and "Data Analysis and Data Visualization" courses.

# Cyber-Physical Systems Group - Technische Universität Wien

Vienna, Austria

PROJECT DEVELOPER Oct. 2018 - Jan. 2019

Project performed on the creation of a vertical farming system during the course of Internet of Things of the Professor Ezio Bartocci at TU Wien.

# **Pubblications**

2023 INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON ROBOTICS AND AUTOMATION (ICRA)

#### **Embodied Agents for Efficient Exploration and Smart Scene Description**

Roberto Bigazzi, Silvia Cascianelli, Lorenzo Baraldi, Marcella Cornia, Rita Cucchiara

2022 ROBOTICS AND AUTOMATION LETTERS (RA-L) + INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON ROBOTICS AND AUTOMATION (ICRA)

#### **Focus on Impact: Indoor Exploration with Intrinsic Motivation**

Roberto Bigazzi, Federico Landi, Silvia Cascianelli, Lorenzo Baraldi, Marcella Cornia, Rita Cucchiara

2022 26TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON PATTERN RECOGNITION (ICPR)

#### Spot the Difference: A Novel Task for Embodied Agents in Changing Environments

Federico Landi, Roberto Bigazzi, Marcella Cornia, Silvia Cascianelli, Lorenzo Baraldi, Rita Cucchiara

2023 22ST INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON IMAGE ANALYSIS AND PROCESSING (ICIAP) (Honorable Mention for ICIAP Best Paper Award)

## **Towards Explainable Embodied Navigation and Recounting**

Samuele Poppi, Roberto Bigazzi, Niyati Rawal, Marcella Cornia, Silvia Cascianelli, Lorenzo Baraldi, Rita Cucchiara

2021 21ST INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON IMAGE ANALYSIS AND PROCESSING (ICIAP)

### **Embodied Navigation at the Art Gallery**

Roberto Bigazzi, Federico Landi, Silvia Cascianelli, Marcella Cornia, Lorenzo Baraldi, Rita Cucchiara

2021 19TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON COMPUTER ANALYSIS OF IMAGES AND PATTERNS (CAIP)

#### Out of the Box: Embodied Navigation in the Real World

Roberto Bigazzi, Federico Landi, Marcella Cornia, Silvia Cascianelli, Lorenzo Baraldi, Rita Cucchiara

2020 25TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON PATTERN RECOGNITION (ICPR) (Oral Presentation)

#### **Explore and Explain: Self-supervised Navigation and Recounting**

Roberto Bigazzi, Federico Landi, Marcella Cornia, Silvia Cascianelli, Lorenzo Baraldi, Rita Cucchiara

UNDER REVIEW

### Indoor Semantic Region Mapping: Language-grounded Visual Recognition for Embodied Navigation

Roberto Bigazzi, Shreyas Kousik, Lorenzo Baraldi, Rita Cucchiara, Marco Pavone

UNDER REVIEW

### AIGeN: An Adversarial Approach for Instruction Generation in Vision-and-Language Navigation

Niyati Rawal, Roberto Bigazzi, Lorenzo Baraldi, Rita Cucchiara

UNDER REVIEW

## UNMuTe: Unifying Navigation and Multimodal Dialogue-like Text Generation

Niyati Rawal, Roberto Bigazzi, Lorenzo Baraldi, Rita Cucchiara

# **Teaching Activities**

2020-23 **Teaching Assistant**, Computer Architectures

2021-22 **Lecturer and Project Tutor**, Al for Automotive

2020-21 **Project Tutor**, Neural Network Computing, Al and Machine Learning for Automotive

2019-20 **Project Tutor**, Computer Vision and Cognitive Systems

# **Program Committees**

Peer Reviewer, IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L)

**Peer Reviewer**, IEEE Geoscience and Remote Sensing Letters (GRSL)

Peer Reviewer, IEEE Pattern Recognition Letters (PRL)

Peer Reviewer, Transactions on Multimedia Computing Communications and Applications (TOMM)

Peer Reviewer, IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)

Peer Reviewer, IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)

Peer Reviewer, IEEE/CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV)

Peer Reviewer, IAPR International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR)

Peer Reviewer, ACM International Conference on Multimedia

According to law 679/2016 of the Regulation of the European Parliament of 27th April 2016, I hereby express my consent to process and use my data provided in this document and application for recruiting purposes.